Guide to the Undergraduate Admissions, Yale University, Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Undergraduate Admissions, Yale University, records of the dean
1899-1992
RU 818
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
28.5
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, surveys, reports and student files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Office of Undergraduate Admissions.
Yale University. Office of Undergraduate Admissions
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 11-A (YRG 11-A), Records of offices responsible for Yale undergraduate admissions and financial aid programs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, surveys, reports and student files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Office of Undergraduate Admissions.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scholarships; Student aid; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Admission; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Admission; Yale University -- Entrance requirements; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Office of Undergraduate Admissions
- Records, 1899-1969; Accession 19ND-A-090
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2045.
  - Office Files
    - 1899-1931 (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
    - 1923-1929 (Box 2, Folder 15-26)
    - 1925-1939 (Box 3, Folder 27-41)
    - 1930-1939 (Box 4, Folder 42-51)
    - 1934-1955 (Box 5, Folder 52-63)
    - 1937-1948 (Box 6, Folder 64-75)
    - 1939-1946 (Box 7, Folder 75-91)
    - 1941-1946 (Box 8, Folder 92-111)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 112-124)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 125-141)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 11)
    - Veteran File Cards, A-G, 1946 (Box 12)
    - Veteran File Cards, H-Z, 1946 (Box 13)
    - Veteran File Cards, A-Z, 1947 (Box 14)
    - 1947-1954 (Box 15, Folder 142-157)
    - 1949-1951 (Box 16, Folder 158-173)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 174-177)
    - 1951 (Box 18, Folder 178-181)
    - 1951 (Box 19, Folder 182-189)
    - 1951 (Box 20, Folder 190-196)
    - 1951 (Box 21, Folder 197-202)
    - 1951-1956 (Box 22, Folder 203-213)
    - 1952 (Box 23, Folder 214-227)
    - 1952-1954 (Box 24, Folder 228-240)
    - 1953 (Box 25, Folder 241-259)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 26, Folder 260-275)
    - 1954 (Box 27, Folder 276-287)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 28, Folder 288-298)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 29, Folder 299-306)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 30, Folder 307-318)
    - 1957 (Box 31, Folder 319-332)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 32, Folder 333-343)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 344-359)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 34, Folder 360-374)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 35, Folder 375-389)
    - 1962 (Box 36, Folder 390-402)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 37, Folder 403-412)
    - 1963 (Box 38, Folder 413-419)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 39, Folder 420-435)
    - 1965-1969 (Box 40, Folder 436-438)
  - School Files
    - 1921-1960
      - A -C (Box 41, Folder 1-10)
      - D - H (Box 42, Folder 11-21)
      - H - M (Box 43, Folder 22-32)
      - N-S (Box 44, Folder 33-41)
      - S - T, miscellaneous (Box 45, Folder 42-50)
      - 1934-1942 (Box 46, Folder 51-54)
      - 1952 (Box 47, Folder 55)
    - 1961-1962
      - A - B (Box 48, Folder 56-57)
      - C - J (Box 49, Folder 58-64)
      - K - P (Box 50, Folder 65-70)
      - S - W (Box 51, Folder 71-76)
  - Ford Foundation
    - 1951-1953 (Box 52, Folder 1-13)
    - 1952-1954 (Box 53, Folder 14-21)
    - 1953 (Box 54, Folder 22-29)
    - 1953-1956 (Box 55, Folder 30-37)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 56, Folder 38-45)
  - Robert N. Corwin Files
    - Angell, James R., 1933-1935 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Articles (R.N. Corwin), 1920-1935 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Association of Class Secretaries, 1947 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Bureau of Appointments, 1927-1930 (Box 57, Folder 4-6)
    - Camp, Walter: index files, 1927 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Carter, George R., 1930-1933 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - College Entrance Examination Board: Committee of Review, 1920-1921 (Box 57, Folder 9-10)
    - College Entrance Examination Board: Committee of Review, 1922-1927 (Box 58, Folder 11-12)
    - College Entrance Examination Board: Executive Committee, 1923-1927 (Box 58, Folder 13-15)
    - Committee on Committees, 1926 (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, general
      - A - R, 1919-1943 (Box 59, Folder 17-23)
      - S - Z, 1919-1943 (Box 60, Folder 24-25)
      - Miscellaneous, 1924-1954 (Box 60, Folder 26-27)
    - Drama department: criticisms, 1928-1936 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - Elliot, Nellie P., 1939-1947 (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Elliot, William Henry, 1938-1945 (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Employment applications for Board of Admissions, 1926-1940 (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Hawaian Trip, 1930-1931 (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - Knaggs, Richard, 1936-1939 (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - Noyes, Edward S. Christmas poems (Box 61, Folder 34)
    - Photographs: R.N. Corwin, 1930 (Box 61, Folder 35)
    - Progressive Education Association, 1932-1937 (Box 61, Folder 36)
    - Progressive schools: record forms, 1937 (Box 61, Folder 37)
    - "Psychology to the General" (R.N. Corwin), 1930-1931 (Box 61, Folder 38-39)
    - Ranking Scholars; the Ten, 1938-1939 (Box 61, Folder 40)
    - Speeches, 1918-1934 (Box 62, Folder 41-45)
    - Undergraduate candidates for Yale Admission, 1951 (Box 62, Folder 46)
    - Undergraduate Faculty Reorganization Committee, 1923-1929 (Box 62, Folder 47-48)
    - University Convocation, 1947 (Box 62, Folder 49)
    - Vallentine, Allen: president, University of Rochester, 1935-1938 (Box 63, Folder 50-53)
- Records of Arthur Howe, Jr. as Dean of Undergraduate Admissions, 1952-1967; Accession 2000-A-038
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2043.
  - A & A writing notes, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admission Policy, 1955, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - High School vs Independent Schools, 1954-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Secondary School Pressures, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Commission Reports on Enrollment, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Robinson, John, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reports to faculty, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notes for talks, 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Talks, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Talks - Articles, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - A & A Notes, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Talks, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Talks, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - K. Brewster, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Colloquium on Financial Aid, 1962 May 13 - 16 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Eligibility Committee, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Colloquium on Financial Aid, 1963 May 12-15 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Radio Programs, 1956-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Kennett Foundation of Conway, N.H., 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Yale Reports, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - New Admission Program, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Travels, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Staff Meetings, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - School Restrictions, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Memorabilia, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Reorganization, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Harvard Nat. Istit.-School Clearance, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ivy Group Finance Office, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Ivy Group Statements, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Freshman Year, President Comm., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Reports to the President, 1954-1962 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - New Yorker Magazine, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Yale Talks Articles, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Notes for Talks, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Notes for Talks, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Notes for Talks, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Outlines of Talks, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Talks, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Talks, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Griswold, A. W., Jr., 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Yale admissions (General), 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Yale Administration Office, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Statistical records and reports of the dean of undergraduate admissions, 1933-1934, 1992; Accession 2001-A-038
  - Report to the president (final draft), 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admission statistics, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)